[
    {
        "question": "Where did the first football world cup take place?",
        "answer1": "Brazil",
        "answer2": "England",
        "answer3": "Uruguay",
        "answer4": "Argentina",
        "correctAnswer": "Uruguay"
    },
    {
        "question": "What United States state has more people than all of Canada?",
        "answer1": "Texas",
        "answer2": "Florida",
        "answer3": "New York",
        "answer4": "California",
        "correctAnswer": "California"
    },
    {
        "question": "What percentage of the Earth's population lives in the Northern Hemisphere?",
        "answer1": "Canada",
        "answer2": "Russia",
        "answer3": "The United Kingdom",
        "answer4": "The United States",
        "correctAnswer": "Canada"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", which character is allergic to regular milk?",
        "answer1": "Bart",
        "answer2": "Ned",
        "answer3": "Milhouse",
        "answer4": "Moe",
        "correctAnswer": "Milhouse"
    },
    {
        "question": "According to Irish superstition, what stands open during the 12 days of Christmas?",
        "answer1": "The enterence to the North Pole",
        "answer2": "The gates of hell",
        "answer3": "The source of immortality",
        "answer4": "The gates of heaven",
        "correctAnswer": "The gates of heaven"
    },
    {
        "question": "Venation is used to describe what item found in nature?",
        "answer1": "Branches",
        "answer2": "Soil",
        "answer3": "Leaves",
        "answer4": "Seeds",
        "correctAnswer": "Leaves"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first pope to visit the White House?",
        "answer1": "Pope Francis",
        "answer2": "Benedict XVI",
        "answer3": "Paul VI",
        "answer4": "John Paul II",
        "correctAnswer": "John Paul II"
    },
    {
        "question": "How many letters are there in the German alphabet?",
        "answer1": "28",
        "answer2": "32",
        "answer3": "26",
        "answer4": "30",
        "correctAnswer": "30"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which city hosted the 2004 Summer Olympic Games?",
        "answer1": "Sydney",
        "answer2": "London",
        "answer3": "Bejing",
        "answer4": "Athens",
        "correctAnswer": "Athens"
    },
    {
        "question": "What animal's head appears on the handle of Mary Poppins' umbrella?",
        "answer1": "A wolf",
        "answer2": "A fox",
        "answer3": "A parrot",
        "answer4": "A cat",
        "correctAnswer": "A parrot"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which country did the first World War I battle take place?",
        "answer1": "France",
        "answer2": "Belgium",
        "answer3": "Germany",
        "answer4": "Austria",
        "correctAnswer": "Belgium"
    },
    {
        "question": "Until 1989, what European country was the world’s second largest exporter of bottled wine?",
        "answer1": "Albania",
        "answer2": "Portugal",
        "answer3": "Greece",
        "answer4": "Bulgaria",
        "correctAnswer": "Bulgaria"
    },
    {
        "question": "In German myth, what river hides the treasure of the Nibelung?",
        "answer1": "Elbe",
        "answer2": "Danube",
        "answer3": "Main",
        "answer4": "The Rhine",
        "correctAnswer": "The Rhine"
    },
    {
        "question": "In Norse mythology, what did Odin trade an eye for?",
        "answer1": "Power",
        "answer2": "Love",
        "answer3": "Wisdom",
        "answer4": "Resurrection",
        "correctAnswer": "Wisdom"
    },
    {
        "question": "What sport did Abe Lincoln play before he was president?",
        "answer1": "Boxing",
        "answer2": "Wrestling",
        "answer3": "Polo",
        "answer4": "Baseball",
        "correctAnswer": "Wrestling"
    },
    {
        "question": "How long is one day on Venus in comparison to Earth?",
        "answer1": "17 hours",
        "answer2": "14 days",
        "answer3": "7 hours",
        "answer4": "8 months",
        "correctAnswer": "8 months"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which sport are barani, rudolph, and randolph all techniques?",
        "answer1": "Trampolining",
        "answer2": "Skateboarding",
        "answer3": "Wrestling",
        "answer4": "Gymnastics",
        "correctAnswer": "Trampolining"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which instrument is associated with Earl ‘Bud’ Powell?",
        "answer1": "Violin",
        "answer2": "Chello",
        "answer3": "Piano",
        "answer4": "Flute",
        "correctAnswer": "Piano"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ‘girl in the polka dot dress’ was an eye witness in whose assassination?",
        "answer1": "John F. Kennedy",
        "answer2": "Franz Ferdinand",
        "answer3": "Robert F. Kennedy",
        "answer4": "James Garfield",
        "correctAnswer": "Robert F. Kennedy"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who’s the only athlete who ever lit the cauldron for an Olympics and then won a gold medal at those same games?",
        "answer1": "Mark Spitz",
        "answer2": "Cathy Freeman",
        "answer3": "Usain Bolt",
        "answer4": "Ray Ewry",
        "correctAnswer": "Cathy Freeman"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the Gilded Age, who was called the “witch of Wallstreet.?",
        "answer1": "Nellie Bly",
        "answer2": "Frank Leslie",
        "answer3": "Caroline Astor",
        "answer4": "Hetty Green",
        "correctAnswer": "Hetty Green"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the largest religious monument in the world?",
        "answer1": "Karnak temple complex",
        "answer2": "Angkor Wat",
        "answer3": "Borodubur",
        "answer4": "Spring temple Buddha",
        "correctAnswer": "Angkor Wat"
    },
    {
        "question": "The red supergiant star, Betelgeuse, belongs to which constellation?",
        "answer1": "Orion the Hunter",
        "answer2": "Hercules",
        "answer3": "Southern crow",
        "answer4": "Perseus",
        "correctAnswer": "Orion the Hunter"
    },
    {
        "question": "The ancient Egyptian symbol “Ouroboros” depicts a serpent eating what?",
        "answer1": "A human eyeball",
        "answer2": "Its own tail",
        "answer3": "A scorpion",
        "answer4": "A rat",
        "correctAnswer": "Its own tail"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who patented the concept of a flat engine in 1896?",
        "answer1": "Etienne Lenoir",
        "answer2": "Karl Benz",
        "answer3": "Alexander Winton",
        "answer4": "Arthur Constantin Krebs",
        "correctAnswer": "Karl Benz"
    },
    {
        "question": "The highest peak of China’s Wuling Mountains is home to two Buddhist temples. How many steps must visitors take to reach the site of these temples called Fanjingshan?",
        "answer1": "10459",
        "answer2": "6066",
        "answer3": "8888",
        "answer4": "14754",
        "correctAnswer": "8888"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the process by which a Komodo Dragon can reproduce asexually?",
        "answer1": "Envirotyping",
        "answer2": "Parthenogenesis",
        "answer3": "Separatiosis",
        "answer4": "Monomorphosis",
        "correctAnswer": "Parthenogenesis"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which author hosted a 1960 fishing competition that Fidel Castro won?",
        "answer1": "Ernest Hemmingway",
        "answer2": "Frank Herbert",
        "answer3": "F. Scott Fitzgerald",
        "answer4": "Erich Maria Remarque",
        "correctAnswer": "Ernest Hemmingway"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the movie \"True Romance\", what was the name of Clarence Worley's love interest?",
        "answer1": "Browning Boyd",
        "answer2": "London Harrison",
        "answer3": "Alabama Whitman",
        "answer4": "Harrold Oxwald",
        "correctAnswer": "Alabama Whitman"
    },
    {
        "question": "What baseball great was nicknamed the Iron Man?",
        "answer1": "Babe Ruth",
        "answer2": "Ty Cobb",
        "answer3": "Willie Mays",
        "answer4": "Cal Ripken Jr.",
        "correctAnswer": "Cal Ripken Jr."
    },
    {
        "question": "Globophobia is the irrational fear of what?",
        "answer1": "Balloons",
        "answer2": "Globes",
        "answer3": "Traveling",
        "answer4": "Waterparks",
        "correctAnswer": "Balloons"
    },
    {
        "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", where was Lenny born?",
        "answer1": "Boston",
        "answer2": "Chicago",
        "answer3": "Portland",
        "answer4": "Washington D.C.",
        "correctAnswer": "Chicago"
    },
    {
        "question": "What band released their 10th studio album under the name \"Back to Us\"?",
        "answer1": "Lady A",
        "answer2": "Dan + Shay",
        "answer3": "Rascal Flatts",
        "answer4": "Florida Georgia Line",
        "correctAnswer": "Rascal Flatts"
    },
    {
        "question": "The 2007 movie \"There Will Be Blood\" is based on which novel by Upton Sinclair?",
        "answer1": "Oil",
        "answer2": "Milk",
        "answer3": "Strangers",
        "answer4": "Visitor",
        "correctAnswer": "Oil"
    },
    {
        "question": "What element did Joseph Priestley discover in 1774?",
        "answer1": "Hydrogen",
        "answer2": "Helium",
        "answer3": "Oxygen",
        "answer4": "Nitrogen",
        "correctAnswer": "Oxygen"
    },
    {
        "question": "The Christmas carol \"Jingle Bells\" was first published in what year?",
        "answer1": "1812",
        "answer2": "1857",
        "answer3": "1901",
        "answer4": "1884",
        "correctAnswer": "1857"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who provided the original voice for Yogi Bear?",
        "answer1": "Don Messick",
        "answer2": "William Hanna",
        "answer3": "Daws Butler",
        "answer4": "Mel Blanc",
        "correctAnswer": "Daws Butler"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pteridophobia is the fear of what?",
        "answer1": "Ferns",
        "answer2": "Forests",
        "answer3": "Roses",
        "answer4": "Sand",
        "correctAnswer": "Ferns"
    },
    {
        "question": "What's the age limit for horses competing in the Kentucky Derby?",
        "answer1": "5-years-old",
        "answer2": "3-years-old",
        "answer3": "4-years-old",
        "answer4": "6-years-old",
        "correctAnswer": "3-years-old"
    },
    {
        "question": "What nearby galaxy is named for a mythological princess?",
        "answer1": "Tucana III",
        "answer2": "Reticulum II",
        "answer3": "Andromeda Galaxy",
        "answer4": "Sextans B",
        "correctAnswer": "Andromeda Galaxy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What boxer is memorialized by a giant fist outside Detroit's Renaissance Center?",
        "answer1": "Sugar Ray Leonard",
        "answer2": "Joe Louis",
        "answer3": "Terence Crawford",
        "answer4": "Andre Ward",
        "correctAnswer": "Joe Louis"
    },
    {
        "question": "What was the first country to declare internet a legal right?",
        "answer1": "Finland",
        "answer2": "Iceland",
        "answer3": "Norway",
        "answer4": "Denmark",
        "correctAnswer": "Finland"
    },
    {
        "question": "When did Mexico declare independence?",
        "answer1": "1916",
        "answer2": "1877",
        "answer3": "1901",
        "answer4": "1810",
        "correctAnswer": "1810"
    },
    {
        "question": "What did Lorraine Chase famously advertise on TV?",
        "answer1": "Bacardi",
        "answer2": "Campari",
        "answer3": "Jack Daniels",
        "answer4": "Aperol",
        "correctAnswer": "Campari"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the only two-term president of the Republic of Texas?",
        "answer1": "David Burnet",
        "answer2": "Mirabeau Lamar",
        "answer3": "Sam Houston",
        "answer4": "Anson Jones",
        "correctAnswer": "Sam Houston"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who is Melanie Griffith's mother?",
        "answer1": "Jessica Tandy",
        "answer2": "Tippi Hedren",
        "answer3": "Suzanne Pleshette",
        "answer4": "Veronica Cartwright",
        "correctAnswer": "Tippi Hedren"
    },
    {
        "question": "Tiger Woods set or tied 27 records at which 1997 PGA tournament?",
        "answer1": "The Masters",
        "answer2": "US Open",
        "answer3": "PGA Championship",
        "answer4": "The British Open Championship",
        "correctAnswer": "The Masters"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which artist was a fashion editor and a painter in the school of magic realism?",
        "answer1": "Frida Kahlo",
        "answer2": "Tichenor",
        "answer3": "Paul Cadmus",
        "answer4": "Werner Tübke",
        "correctAnswer": "Tichenor"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who wrote the poem \"Anthem for Doomed Youth\"?",
        "answer1": "Wilfred Owen",
        "answer2": "Siegfried Sassoon",
        "answer3": "Rupert Brooke",
        "answer4": "Isaac Rosenberg",
        "correctAnswer": "Wilfred Owen"
    },
    {
        "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"The Autobiography of a Horse\"?",
        "answer1": "Who was Seabiscuit?",
        "answer2": "Black Beauty",
        "answer3": "The Black Stallion",
        "answer4": "Riding Lessons",
        "correctAnswer": "Black Beauty"
    },
    {
        "question": "What conflict is sometimes called the African World War?",
        "answer1": "Somali Civil War",
        "answer2": "Nigerian Civil War",
        "answer3": "Eritrean-Ethiopian War",
        "answer4": "Second Congo War",
        "correctAnswer": "Second Congo War"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which TV show used the song \"Who Are You\" by the Who as its theme song?",
        "answer1": "CSI Miami",
        "answer2": "CSI",
        "answer3": "NCIS",
        "answer4": "Criminal Minds",
        "correctAnswer": "CSI"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the name of the agreement that ended the Soviet Union?",
        "answer1": "Tashkent Agreement",
        "answer2": "Warsaw Pact",
        "answer3": "Belavezha Accords",
        "answer4": "Linggadjati Agreement",
        "correctAnswer": "Belavezha Accords"
    },
    {
        "question": "What does the \"touch of Midas\" turn everything into?",
        "answer1": "Silver",
        "answer2": "Ash",
        "answer3": "Bronze",
        "answer4": "Gold",
        "correctAnswer": "Gold"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the real first name of the singer Boy George?",
        "answer1": "James",
        "answer2": "George",
        "answer3": "Garrett",
        "answer4": "Jeffrey",
        "correctAnswer": "James"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which Constitutional amendment gave Congress the power to levy tax on personal incomes?",
        "answer1": "19th",
        "answer2": "13th",
        "answer3": "10th",
        "answer4": "16th",
        "correctAnswer": "16th"
    },
    {
        "question": "Under what pseudonym did Charles Dickens write his first books?",
        "answer1": "Lov",
        "answer2": "Boz",
        "answer3": "Kas",
        "answer4": "Nes",
        "correctAnswer": "Boz"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is a plant with no internal system of tube-like structures called?",
        "answer1": "Dicranum",
        "answer2": "Polytrichum",
        "answer3": "Nonvascular",
        "answer4": "Sphagnum",
        "correctAnswer": "Nonvascular"
    },
    {
        "question": "What cut of steak got its name from the New York City coach stop where it was first served?",
        "answer1": "Ribeye",
        "answer2": "Hanger",
        "answer3": "Porterhouse",
        "answer4": "Sirloin",
        "correctAnswer": "Porterhouse"
    },
    {
        "question": "In which 1966 science fiction film did Stephen Boyd star alongside Raquel Welch?",
        "answer1": "Barbarella",
        "answer2": "Marooned",
        "answer3": "War of the Planets",
        "answer4": "Fantastic Voyage",
        "correctAnswer": "Fantastic Voyage"
    },
    {
        "question": "What late Texas blues rocker was backed by a group called Double Trouble?",
        "answer1": "Eric Clapton",
        "answer2": "Jeff Black",
        "answer3": "Stevie Ray Vaughan",
        "answer4": "Albert King",
        "correctAnswer": "Stevie Ray Vaughan"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who wrote the humorous novel \"The Life and Opinions of Tristram Shandy, Gentleman\"?",
        "answer1": "Samuel Richardson",
        "answer2": "Henry Fielding",
        "answer3": "Jonathan Swift",
        "answer4": "Laurence Sterne",
        "correctAnswer": "Laurence Sterne"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who recruits Tony to the F.D.A. in the comic series \"Chew\"?",
        "answer1": "John Colby",
        "answer2": "Mason Savoy",
        "answer3": "D-Bear",
        "answer4": "Mike Applebee",
        "correctAnswer": "Mason Savoy"
    },
    {
        "question": "What year saw the debut of the comic book character Wonder Woman?",
        "answer1": "1956",
        "answer2": "1962",
        "answer3": "1939",
        "answer4": "1941",
        "correctAnswer": "1941"
    },
    {
        "question": "What sci-fi series, which debuted in 1965, took place in the year 1997?",
        "answer1": "Lost in Space",
        "answer2": "Star Trek",
        "answer3": "Dr. Who",
        "answer4": "The Time Tunnel",
        "correctAnswer": "Lost in Space"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the fear of the number 13 known as?",
        "answer1": "Arachibutyrophobia",
        "answer2": "Triskaidekaphobia",
        "answer3": "Arithmophobia",
        "answer4": "Ablutophobia",
        "correctAnswer": "Triskaidekaphobia"
    },
    {
        "question": "On what date did singer, songwriter, and actor David Bowie die?",
        "answer1": "17-Sep-18",
        "answer2": "23-Oct-16",
        "answer3": "10-Jan-16",
        "answer4": "18-Feb-14",
        "correctAnswer": "10-Jan-16"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where was the first mobile automaton, named \"Beast\", built in?",
        "answer1": "Harvard University",
        "answer2": "Duke University",
        "answer3": "University of Texas, Austin",
        "answer4": "John Hopkins University",
        "correctAnswer": "John Hopkins University"
    },
    {
        "question": "Who was the first performer at the Woodstock festival in 1969?",
        "answer1": "Sweetwater",
        "answer2": "Richie Havens",
        "answer3": "Sri Swami Satchidananda",
        "answer4": "Bert Sommer",
        "correctAnswer": "Richie Havens"
    },
    {
        "question": "In The Simpsons, who is Lisa's favorite jazz musician?",
        "answer1": "Billie Holiday",
        "answer2": "Charles Mingus",
        "answer3": "Bleeding Gums Murphy",
        "answer4": "Charlie Parker",
        "correctAnswer": "Bleeding Gums Murphy"
    }
]

